A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4 FA276
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
1919-2002
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA276
3.61 Cubic Feet 9 document boxes and 1 half-document box, 11 bound volumes
Location note
Annual Reports for 2000-2013 are available online at the Commonwealth Fund website.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical/Historical note
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Scope and Contents
Series 4 contains annual reports from 1919-2002. A complete run of bound reports is available in the RAC Library. Individual soft cover reports are available in the archival collection. The Annual Report for 1986 is not available in the archival collection, but it is accessible in the RAC Library. Series 4 also contains a small selection of other reports and pamphlets spanning the mid-1980's through 1994.
Public health; Public welfare; New York (N.Y.); New York (State); United States; War relief; Law; Hygiene; Legal research; Legal issues; Child psychology; Child mental health; Education, Rural; Child welfare; Mental health; Medical education; Medical research; Medicine, Rural; Medicine -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Annual reports
- 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1921 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Draft, 1926; 2 drafts. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1927 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Draft, 1927; 2 drafts. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1928 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Draft, 1928; 2 drafts. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Draft, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1930 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Draft, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 1931 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 1932 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 1933 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 1934 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 1935 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- 1936 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- 1937 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- 1938 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 1939 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- 1940 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- 1941 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- 1942 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- 1943 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- 1944 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- 1945 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- 1946 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- 1947 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- 1948 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- 1949 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- 1950 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- 1951 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- 1952 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- 1953 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- 1954 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- 1955 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- 1956 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- 1957 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- 1958, 2 copies. (Box 4, Folder 40)
- 1959, 2 copies. (Box 4, Folder 41)
- 1960 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- 1961 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- 1962, 2 copies. (Box 4, Folder 44)
- 1963 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- 1964 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- 1965 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- 1966, 2 copies. (Box 4, Folder 48)
- 1968 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Introduction only, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- 1971 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- 1972 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- 1973 (Box 5, Folder 54)
- 1975 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 56)
- 1976 (Box 6, Folder 57)
- 1977 (Box 6, Folder 58)
- 1978 (Box 6, Folder 59)
- 1979 (Box 7, Folder 60)
- 1980, 2 copies. (Box 7, Folder 61)
- 1981, 2 copies. (Box 7, Folder 62)
- 1982, 2 copies. (Box 7, Folder 63)
- 1983, 2 copies. (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Mentors, 1983; 2 copies. (Box 7, Folder 64)
- 1984, 2 copies. (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Leaders, 1984; 2 copies. (Box 7, Folder 65)
- 1985, 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 66)
- 1986
- 1987, 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 67)
- 1988, 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 68)
- 1989, 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1989; 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 69)
- 1990 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1990; 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 70)
- 1991, 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1991; 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 71)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 1992 (Item REF 941.063 COM 1992)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 1993 (Item REF 941.063 COM 1993)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 1994 (Item REF 941.063 COM 1994)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 1995 (Item REF 941.063 COM 1995)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 1996 (Item REF 941.063 COM 1996)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 1997 (Item REF 941.063 COM 1997)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 1998 (Item REF 941.063 COM 1998)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 1999 (Item REF 941.063 COM 1999)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 2000 (Item REF 941.063 2000)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 2001 (Item REF 941.063 COM 2001)
- Commonwealth Fund Annual Report 2002 (Item REF 941.063 COM 2002)
- 1992, 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Builders, 1992; 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Executive Vice President's Report on Major Programs, 1992; 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1992; 2 copies. (Box 8, Folder 72)
- 1993, 2 copies. (Box 9, Folder 73)
- 1994 (Box 9, Folder 74)
- 1995, 2 copies. (Box 9, Folder 75)
- 1996, 2 copies. (Box 9, Folder 76)
- 1997, 2 copies. (Box 9, Folder 77)
- Other Reports, 1985-1986, 1994
  - Report on the Task Force of Academic Health Centers, 1985; 2 copies. (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - For the Common Good: The Commonwealth Fund, 1918-1993., 1994 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Press Information
    - Task Force on Academic Health Centers, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - Elderly People Living Alone, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 81)
- Pamphlets, 1983-1986
  - Career Beginnings Program, 1986 January; 2 copies. (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Executive Nurse Fellowship Program, 1986 January; 2 copies. (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Executive Nurse Leadership Program (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - 1983 December, 2 copies. (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - 1984 June, 2 copies. (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - At Boston University, 1985 August 25-November 15 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - At the Medical College of Virginia / Virginia Commonwealth University, 2 copies. (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Financial Condition of New York City Voluntary Hospitals: The First Year of NYPHRM (United Hospital Fund of New York), Paper Series 2, 1985 December (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Fellowship Program in Academic Medicine for Minority Students, 1985; 2 copies. (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - The Frontiers of Science (Announcement of the Commonwealth Fund Book Program), 1984 March; 2 copies. (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Task Force on Academic Health Centers, 1983 November (Box 10, Folder 88)